<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure on Midnight Programmer</title>
    <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/category/azure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Azure on Midnight Programmer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 16:54:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/category/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hosting Draw.IO In Azure Web App Containers</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/hosting-drawio-in-azure-webapp-containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 16:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/hosting-drawio-in-azure-webapp-containers/</guid>
      <description>Draw.IO is a great alternative for Microsoft Visio. It allows me to quickly draw flowcharts and diagrams. I have been using this for a long time and the best part is that Draw.IO is open source on Github with web and offline (desktop) version. I personally use desktop version but what if I would like to host it in my own org or would like to work with the web instance instead of the desktop version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extract Text From Images Using Computer Vision API And Azure Function</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/extract-text-from-images-using-computer-vision-api-and-azure-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 15:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/extract-text-from-images-using-computer-vision-api-and-azure-function/</guid>
      <description>I started to work on a project which is a combination of lot of intelligent APIs and Machine Learning stuff. One of the things I have to accomplish is to extract the text from the images that are being uploaded to the storage. To accomplish this part of the project I planned to use Microsoft Cognitive Service Computer Vision API. Here is the extract of it from my architecture diagram.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enable Multi Factor Authentication (MFA) For Users In Azure Active Directory</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/enable-multi-factor-authentication-mfa-for-users-in-azure-active-directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 14:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/enable-multi-factor-authentication-mfa-for-users-in-azure-active-directory/</guid>
      <description>A video tutorial on how you can enable Multi Factor Authentication or MFA as it is called, for the users in the Azure Active Directory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hosting ASP.NET Core Web Application On Azure Linux VM</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/hosting-aspnet-core-web-application-on-azure-linux-vm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 16:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/hosting-aspnet-core-web-application-on-azure-linux-vm/</guid>
      <description>I run this blog on Azure as a Web App. I was planning to host it using a VM just for fun but I dropped the idea and choose Web Apps for my blog as a simple medium with less deployment effort and no server management at all. This blog post is mostly me documenting the steps to deploy or host the application on an Azure Linux Virtual Machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single Sign-On In ASP.NET Core With Azure Active Directory</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/single-sign-on-in-aspnet-core-with-azure-active-directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 15:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/single-sign-on-in-aspnet-core-with-azure-active-directory/</guid>
      <description>Visual Studio has made integrating of Azure Active Directory authentication in web applications very simple. If you are creating the application and want to integrate the AD authentication then it is a pretty easy task given that you have an Active Directory in Azure. But what if you have an application and it is out there running and now you want to change the authentication medium of your application so you can have better control and security of your web application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Web Based Temperature/Humidity Monitor App With Raspberry PI 3 and Azure IoT Hub</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/building-web-based-temperaturehumidity-monitor-app-with-raspberry-pi-3-and-azure-iot-hub/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 07:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/building-web-based-temperaturehumidity-monitor-app-with-raspberry-pi-3-and-azure-iot-hub/</guid>
      <description>I was planning to build a web based temperature/humidity monitoring app with Raspberry PI 3 and Windows 10 IoT Core. I have playing around with Raspbian for a while now and this time I wanted to try something different. I have been using Python to write application for Raspberry PI, Windows IoT Core with C# will be something new for me and therefore, this time I choose to go with Windows 10 IoT Core.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free E-Book: Understanding Azure - A Guide For Developers</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/free-e-book-understanding-azure-a-guide-for-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 20:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/free-e-book-understanding-azure-a-guide-for-developers/</guid>
      <description>There is no time better to be a developer. With the cloud, you can compose solutions that were never possible before. You can release new features to millions of users within minutes. You can push the boundaries of current technological limitations in days. Developers can turn ideas from the ground up to successful businesses in only months. Companies need apps that allow them to maximize customer engagement and differentiate against competitors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML5 Video - Capture And Upload Image To Azure Storage</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/html5-video-capture-and-upload-image-to-azure-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 23:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/html5-video-capture-and-upload-image-to-azure-storage/</guid>
      <description>I was exploring Github for some image effects/filters and I found some but still keep exploring and found an interesting plugin called face-detection. This plugin uses HTML5 getUserMedia to use your web camera only if your browser supports it. Unfortunately, IE10 still doesn’t support it. This seems cool to me, so I created a sample application to test it. This sample application will let you preview the video using your web camera and allows you to capture the image from your web camera and upload it to the Azure storage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Launches SkyDrive Application For Windows</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/microsoft-launches-skydrive-application-for-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 13:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/microsoft-launches-skydrive-application-for-windows/</guid>
      <description>On 23rd April Microsoft announces the launch of official SkyDrive application for Windows on Windows 8 blog. This is one of the most awaited applications among the developers and users. All we wanted is a simple app through which we can manage our cloud storage with ease. Download the SkyDrive app here.
Here is what available now according to this blog post:
  SkyDrive for the Windows desktop (preview available now).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Use Of Windows SkyDrive</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/efficient-use-of-windows-skydrive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2010 16:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/efficient-use-of-windows-skydrive/</guid>
      <description>If you are not using this free service offered by Microsoft, then stop reading and go to SkyDrive and sign in with your Live ID and get started. A whooping 25 GB of free space to put all your stuff at one place, access anytime, and anywhere you want and just in case if you are aware, which I hope you already are, why I am mentioning about skydrive here? So, here is the case&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage your Azure storage with ease!</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/manage-your-azure-storage-with-ease-with-azure-storage-explorer-and-cloud-storage-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2009 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/manage-your-azure-storage-with-ease-with-azure-storage-explorer-and-cloud-storage-studio/</guid>
      <description>If your are using Windows Azure for storing files here are the tools you should love to use to manage your Azure cloud storage.
Azure Storage Explorer
And
Cloud Storage Studio
If you don&amp;rsquo;t have an Azure account, then have one HERE</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>