<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Midnight Programmer</title>
    <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Midnight Programmer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 12:13:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Capture screenshot and description of a web page using Go and Chromedp</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/capture-screenshot-and-description-of-a-web-page-using-go-and-chromedp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 12:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/capture-screenshot-and-description-of-a-web-page-using-go-and-chromedp/</guid>
      <description>Adding or sharing a link with a snapshot of a web page is a very useful feature in Microsoft Teams or in Zoom chat. This gives a user a way to quickly look at the web page snapshot and a small description about the link.
Go has an amazing library called chromedp which allows you to perform some amazing tasks like taking screenshot, fill out a form and submit it, send key events, device emulation, script evaluation etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marvel Comics Universe Graph Database</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/marvel-comics-universe-graph-db/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 10:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/marvel-comics-universe-graph-db/</guid>
      <description>In the past decade Marvel has gathered a lot of fans following which eventually led all the fans to know more about how the Marvel comics universe characters, stories, events are mapped or linked to each other.
In 2017 (if I am remembering it correctly), at Microsoft Build event, Microsoft announces Bot framework and did a demo with CosmosDB graph database which uses Gremlin query from Apache TinkerPop. It was a great demo, and I was really impressed by how they did it but unfortunately, I was unable to find the source code for that demo anywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing OpenFaaS On k3s (Single Node)</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/installing-openfaas-on-k3s-single-node/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 20:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/installing-openfaas-on-k3s-single-node/</guid>
      <description>If you have ever got your hands on Azure Function or on AWS Lambda, then you might be familiar with the concept of serverless computing. So in order to test the concept of a function (serverless function), we have to have an Azure or an AWS account. The SDK from both the platforms allow you to build, develop and test the functions on your local development machine, but when it comes to production environment, you again have to turn yourself to Azure or AWS for hosting it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hosting Draw.IO In Azure Web App Containers</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/hosting-drawio-in-azure-webapp-containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 05:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/hosting-drawio-in-azure-webapp-containers/</guid>
      <description>Draw.IO is a great alternative for Microsoft Visio. It allows me to quickly draw flowcharts and diagrams. I have been using this for a long time and the best part is that Draw.IO is open source on Github with web and offline (desktop) version. I personally use desktop version but what if I would like to host it in my own org or would like to work with the web instance instead of the desktop version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create, Mount And Unmount .img Files In Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/create-mount-and-unmount-img-files-in-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 15:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/create-mount-and-unmount-img-files-in-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Recently I moved from Windows to Ubuntu on one of my laptops and since then I was trying to look for the way to create a VHDs or some sort of image files that I can use as a container. So I looked up for the solution and found a working solution scattered though places. So here I am putting it in a blog post to have all it in one place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extract Text From Images Using Computer Vision API And Azure Function</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/extract-text-from-images-using-computer-vision-api-and-azure-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 15:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/extract-text-from-images-using-computer-vision-api-and-azure-function/</guid>
      <description>I started to work on a project which is a combination of lot of intelligent APIs and Machine Learning stuff. One of the things I have to accomplish is to extract the text from the images that are being uploaded to the storage. To accomplish this part of the project I planned to use Microsoft Cognitive Service Computer Vision API. Here is the extract of it from my architecture diagram.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enable Multi Factor Authentication (MFA) For Users In Azure Active Directory</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/enable-multi-factor-authentication-mfa-for-users-in-azure-active-directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 14:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/enable-multi-factor-authentication-mfa-for-users-in-azure-active-directory/</guid>
      <description>A video tutorial on how you can enable Multi Factor Authentication or MFA as it is called, for the users in the Azure Active Directory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hosting ASP.NET Core Web Application On Azure Linux VM</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/hosting-aspnet-core-web-application-on-azure-linux-vm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 16:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/hosting-aspnet-core-web-application-on-azure-linux-vm/</guid>
      <description>I run this blog on Azure as a Web App. I was planning to host it using a VM just for fun but I dropped the idea and choose Web Apps for my blog as a simple medium with less deployment effort and no server management at all. This blog post is mostly me documenting the steps to deploy or host the application on an Azure Linux Virtual Machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single Sign-On In ASP.NET Core With Azure Active Directory</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/single-sign-on-in-aspnet-core-with-azure-active-directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 15:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/single-sign-on-in-aspnet-core-with-azure-active-directory/</guid>
      <description>Visual Studio has made integrating of Azure Active Directory authentication in web applications very simple. If you are creating the application and want to integrate the AD authentication then it is a pretty easy task given that you have an Active Directory in Azure. But what if you have an application and it is out there running and now you want to change the authentication medium of your application so you can have better control and security of your web application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Web Based Temperature/Humidity Monitor App With Raspberry PI 3 and Azure IoT Hub</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/building-web-based-temperaturehumidity-monitor-app-with-raspberry-pi-3-and-azure-iot-hub/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 07:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/building-web-based-temperaturehumidity-monitor-app-with-raspberry-pi-3-and-azure-iot-hub/</guid>
      <description>I was planning to build a web based temperature/humidity monitoring app with Raspberry PI 3 and Windows 10 IoT Core. I have playing around with Raspbian for a while now and this time I wanted to try something different. I have been using Python to write application for Raspberry PI, Windows IoT Core with C# will be something new for me and therefore, this time I choose to go with Windows 10 IoT Core.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upload Files In .NET Core By Drag And Drop Using Dropzone.JS</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/upload-files-in-net-core-by-drag-and-drop-using-dropzonejs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 21:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/upload-files-in-net-core-by-drag-and-drop-using-dropzonejs/</guid>
      <description>Mostly all web applications out there has some way or the other amazing ways to upload a single or multiple files. While surfing on Github I found this amazing library to upload the files to the server in a unique way with lot of configurations. It support parallel uploads along with cancellation of the files which are in the upload queue along with a good looking progress bar to show the progress of upload.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free E-Book: Understanding Azure - A Guide For Developers</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/free-e-book-understanding-azure-a-guide-for-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 20:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/free-e-book-understanding-azure-a-guide-for-developers/</guid>
      <description>There is no time better to be a developer. With the cloud, you can compose solutions that were never possible before. You can release new features to millions of users within minutes. You can push the boundaries of current technological limitations in days. Developers can turn ideas from the ground up to successful businesses in only months. Companies need apps that allow them to maximize customer engagement and differentiate against competitors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get The Correct File Paths In .NET Core</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/get-the-correct-file-paths-in-net-core/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 22:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/get-the-correct-file-paths-in-net-core/</guid>
      <description>I run a custom blog engine I wrote myself on MVC 4 and as you would have thought it is on Windows hosting. I am re-writing my blog engine in .NET Core so that I can get it running on a Linux hosting as well. I am using Windows machine and Visual Studio Community Edition to write it and using a Ubuntu VM box to test it. My current blog uses SQL Server as a back-end but Linux does not support SQL Server and therefore I have to move to MySQL or any other No-SQL database available for Linux distros.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing ADXL345 Accelerometer Output In Windows Forms From Raspberry PI 2</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/visualizing-adxl345-accelerometer-output-in-windows-forms-from-raspberry-pi-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 21:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/visualizing-adxl345-accelerometer-output-in-windows-forms-from-raspberry-pi-2/</guid>
      <description>I have been playing a lot with Raspberry PI and Python these days and have also started a side project to create robot car controller with a Xbox 360 wireless controller. I am planning to controller a robot car using a custom interface from my Windows machine. Initially I tried with PyQt but I dropped the idea for now as Python is not my primary expertise and it will take some time for me to learn the basics and get into some serious coding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Angular 2 App With Web API And .NET Core</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/building-angular-2-app-with-web-api-and-net-core/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 18:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/building-angular-2-app-with-web-api-and-net-core/</guid>
      <description>Setting up the new Angular 2 app with Web API and .NET core is easy but can be a bit tricky. The older beta releases of Angular 2 works fine as there are not many files to refer and to work with. When I started using Angular 2 it was in RC1 and the way the files are being referenced in the app is bit different than the older versions of Angular 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Buzz #3 - Bookmarks</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/dev-buzz-3-bookmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2016 13:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/dev-buzz-3-bookmarks/</guid>
      <description>.NET Core  GitHub Authentication with ASP.NET Core Social TagHelpers for ASP.NET Core Dependency Injection in ASP.NET Core ASP.NET Core: Custom Service Based on Request  Visual Studio/Visual Studio Code  Setting up ASP.NET Core debugging in VS Code What’s new for the .NET Native Compiler and Runtime in Visual Studio 2015 Update 2 What’s New for C# and VB in Visual Studio Tips for Speeding Up Visual Studio  Open Source  Corebird - Native GTK+ Twitter Client OpenLiveWriter - WLW  Miscellaneous  16 Things To Do After Installing Ubuntu 16.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parsing Markdown Using Custom TagHelper In ASP.NET MVC 6</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/markdown-parser-taghelper-in-aspnet-mvc-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 21:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/markdown-parser-taghelper-in-aspnet-mvc-6/</guid>
      <description>Previous versions of MVC allows us to write HtmlHelpers which does a pretty good job then and they are doing it now as well. But in MVC 6, the ASP.NET team has introduced TagHelpers.
Parsing Markdown in .NET is way too simple than one can imagine. Thanks to Stackoverflow&amp;rsquo;s MarkdownSharp and Karlis Gangis&amp;rsquo;s CommonMark.NET. I use CommonMark.NET as it provides a much faster parsing than other libraries. The blogging platform I use is a custom blogging engine I wrote in MVC4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free E-Book: 52 Tips &amp; Tricks to Boost .NET Performance from Redgate</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/free-e-book-52-tips-tricks-to-boost-net-performance-from-redgate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 08:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/free-e-book-52-tips-tricks-to-boost-net-performance-from-redgate/</guid>
      <description> A super awesome free e-book from our friends at RedGate.
 52 tips from the .NET community for boosting performance in your applications. Learn the secrets of your fellow developers and read advice from MVPs and other experts. Covers .NET and ASP.NET, database access, memory usage, and more&amp;hellip;  Download Now </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Controlling 16x2 LCD With Raspberry PI 2 Using Adafruit Library</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/controlling-16x2-lcd-with-raspberry-pi-2-using-adafruit-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 12:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/controlling-16x2-lcd-with-raspberry-pi-2-using-adafruit-library/</guid>
      <description>As an enthusiast, I started working with embedded with Netduino. It was fun but at the same time Netduino was not offering that much things that I can do now. For a person like me who has no knowledge of electronics and C/C++, this was a gift. Now here I am using Raspberry PI&amp;rsquo;s latest version and I have everything I ever wanted on a single piece of hardware.
To get started with Python and Raspberry PI, I looked into the &amp;ldquo;Hello World&amp;rdquo; sort of LED blinking example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Projects You Should Be Following On Github</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/net-projects-you-should-be-follwing-on-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 13:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/net-projects-you-should-be-follwing-on-github/</guid>
      <description>Open-source has entirely change the programming and developers world. Today you can create any application, game, mobile app without spending a single penny. Thanks to open-source software and awesome community of developers and people behind them. As a .NET developer I have been developing enterprise applications for quite a long time and now I have shifted my focus towards developing products and understanding what it takes to make a successful product launch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With ASP.NET 5 On Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/getting-started-with-aspnet-5-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 22:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/getting-started-with-aspnet-5-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Ever since the .NET stack went open source last year, there is a huge excitement among the developers about the .NET stuff and developing apps using .NET which are no longer limited to Windows platform. I tried to install ASP.NET VNext on Ubuntu VM in which I terribly failed in the first go. Why? because the tutorial I used was quite old and I messed up the installation of pre-requisites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free e-Books From Microsoft And Telerik That You Should Be Reading</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/free-e-books-from-microsoft-and-telerik-that-you-should-be-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 08:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/free-e-books-from-microsoft-and-telerik-that-you-should-be-reading/</guid>
      <description>I am involving myself in reading book these days rather than reading blogs. Here are 2 free e-books, one from Microsoft Press with a valuable insights on Cloud, Fundamental of Azure and the other from Telerik, The Developer&#39;s Guide To The New .NET. I encourage you to read both the books, but if you are not about cloud then you should read the book from Telerik.
Microsoft Press - Fundamentals of Azure (Download)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Generic The Code Can Be - Resolving Type T at Compile Time</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/how-generic-the-code-can-be-resolving-type-t-at-compile-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2015 08:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/how-generic-the-code-can-be-resolving-type-t-at-compile-time/</guid>
      <description>It is fun working with Generics, but sometimes it just won&amp;rsquo;t work as I intended it to work. While working on a personal project, I was trying to write the code as generic as possible so I can re-use the functions or extension methods in my other projects as well. But it is not always the case, things will not always work as you want it to be. Here is the case of what I was trying to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recurring Tasks Inside ASP.NET Applications Using HangFire</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/recurring-tasks-inside-aspnet-applications-using-hangfire/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2014 07:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/recurring-tasks-inside-aspnet-applications-using-hangfire/</guid>
      <description>This is open-source at its best. Running background task to work in context with ASP.NET was and is still a big deal for few developers. I user QueueUserWorkItem to schedule emails when a new comment is added on my blog. This makes sure that the UI is responsive and the user can close or navigate to other post. I have been working on enterprise applications for many years now and most of the long running tasks are running in the background i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Real Time Applications With Firebase And AngularJS</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/building-real-time-applications-with-firebase-and-angularjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2014 23:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/building-real-time-applications-with-firebase-and-angularjs/</guid>
      <description>Building real-time applications with SignalR is easy. But building real-time applications with JavaScript will be a problem if you are not aware of Firebase. I first heard of it when I was learning AngularJS. The official AngularJS site has the example where you can add, edit and delete the detials in real-time. This example uses Firebase as the storage and updates the UI in real time.
The data is stored in JSON format and accessing it using jQuery makes it very easy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turn Your Google Drive Folder In An Online Album Viewer</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/turn-your-google-drive-folder-in-an-online-album-viewer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 15:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/turn-your-google-drive-folder-in-an-online-album-viewer/</guid>
      <description>Working with Google Drive API is fun. The documentation is good and will let you get started with the API pretty quickly. I have my whole complete family album on OneDrive, but the API is still a bit hard to use as compared to Google Drive API or maybe it is just for me. But while playing around with Drive API I ended up creating a small razor based web page application which will allow you to show your folder as an online web album.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JSON Based Document Storage Using Biggy In ASP.NET MVC</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/json-based-document-storage-using-biggy-in-aspnet-mvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2014 13:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/json-based-document-storage-using-biggy-in-aspnet-mvc/</guid>
      <description>While working with a small web based project many developers will take advantage of web.config and XML files to read settings for the application. Using web.config is a good way but you cannot change the settings from within the application and when done manually it causes the website to restart. XML is good but many of us has a problem when it comes to update the details in XML. Biggy is an awesome library developed by Rob Conery to work with document storage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Blogging Engine!</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/new-blogging-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 15:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/new-blogging-engine/</guid>
      <description>I like Wordpress but not as much as I like BlogEngine.NET. I have to move to Wordpress because of a very serious issue in BlogEngine.NET. I am on a shared hosting and they are very peculiar about the memory/CPU usage of a site. So, The problem I faced was that if I use SQL Server CE as your data store than it will increase the disk usage time which in turn shuts down my site application pool and cause 503 service unavailable error.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Desktop Notifications In HTML5</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/desktop-notifications-in-html5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2013 22:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/desktop-notifications-in-html5/</guid>
      <description>If you are using Google chat on your browser you can see a notification pop-up when a new chat message arrives. I don’t use Google chat or GTalk a lot for communication so I am not very well versed about its over all functionality and coolness. But one thing that always got my attention in the past was the notification that I get on my desktop from Google. This is a very cool feature and my colleagues find it a very important feature of chat as it get their attention immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Buzz #2 - Bookmarks - 1 JUL 2013</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/dev-buzz-2-bookmarks-1-jul-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 21:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/dev-buzz-2-bookmarks-1-jul-2013/</guid>
      <description>Awesome Stuff  Windows 8.1 sample apps Postman – Chrome based REST client Modern.IE – Testing for IE Visual Studio 2013 for Web developers – Build Webcast – Mads Kristensen Lotaris – A new way to monetize your Windows 8 apps Entensionmethods.net – A site dedicate to Extension Methods cURL for Windows  Web Development  TypeScript EISK - Employee Info Starter Kit AngularJS and TypeScript Adding Ninject to Web API 20 JavaScript Frameworks: MVVM Templating, Licenses etc One to one chat using ASP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSDN Style Syntax Highlighting In ASP.NET</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/msdn-style-syntax-highlighting-in-aspnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 01:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/msdn-style-syntax-highlighting-in-aspnet/</guid>
      <description>There are many syntax highlighting plugins available on the web right now. Majority of the sites are using javascript based Syntax Highlighter from Alex Gorbatchev. I am using it for my current blog and BlogEngine.NET has it as a default syntax highlighter. It is good because it has a lot of themes to offer and you can also customize according to the look and feel of your blog or site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With Glimpse In ASP.NET MVC</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/getting-started-with-glimpse-in-aspnet-mvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2013 22:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/getting-started-with-glimpse-in-aspnet-mvc/</guid>
      <description>When I heard about Glimpse, I thought it like to be another MiniProfiler like stuff or a combination of MiniProfiler and this. But it seems to be more robust diagnostic tool for developers. Here is my experience with this awesome diagnostic tool.
What is Glimpse? Glimpse is a diagnostic tool for ASP.NET applications which let you see detailed diagnostic information of your web application. Glimpse knows everything your server is doing and displays it straight away to you in your browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Buzz #1 - Bookmarks - 19 JUN 2013</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/dev-buzz-1-bookmarks-19-jun-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 20:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/dev-buzz-1-bookmarks-19-jun-2013/</guid>
      <description>ASP.NET/MVC/Web  4 new single page application templates Deploying an Azure website from Source Control Collaborative route planner with SignalR, Knockout.JS and Google Maps Using Require.JS in an ASP.NET MVC application Getting started with Glimpse in ASP.NET MVC Five essential front-end tools that should be used with modern MVC projects  JQuery  JWERTY – Awesome handling of keyboard events JustGage - JustGage is a handy JavaScript plugin for generating and animating nice &amp;amp; clean gauges Spritely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer Buzz (Dev Buzz) - Sharing My Bookmarks</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/developer-buzz-dev-buzz-sharing-my-bookmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 11:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/developer-buzz-dev-buzz-sharing-my-bookmarks/</guid>
      <description>Dev Buzz is an abbreviated form of Developer Buzz which will be a carrier of my bookmarks. There is no point of saving me a bookmark if I can’t share out with other developers (this is my thought on bookmarks). Therefore, from today onward I’ll be doing a blog post week or may be monthly to share by bookmark with the rest of you guys and moreover I have a huge collection of funny programmer pics which also accompany my bookmarks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML5 Video - Capture And Upload Image To Azure Storage</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/html5-video-capture-and-upload-image-to-azure-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 23:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/html5-video-capture-and-upload-image-to-azure-storage/</guid>
      <description>I was exploring Github for some image effects/filters and I found some but still keep exploring and found an interesting plugin called face-detection. This plugin uses HTML5 getUserMedia to use your web camera only if your browser supports it. Unfortunately, IE10 still doesn’t support it. This seems cool to me, so I created a sample application to test it. This sample application will let you preview the video using your web camera and allows you to capture the image from your web camera and upload it to the Azure storage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building MVC Application With Multiple Database Support Using Ninject</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/building-mvc-application-with-multiple-database-support-using-ninject/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 14:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/building-mvc-application-with-multiple-database-support-using-ninject/</guid>
      <description>I used to have BlogEngine.NET as my blogging platform before switching to WordPress, and that is because of my poor hosting provider who can’t afford few MBs on the shared hosting plans. I like BlogEngine.NET a lot because it is in .NET and on the other hand WordPress is on PHP which I don’t know. BlogEngine.NET is still evolving and is getting better with every release. BlogEngine.NET supports multiple databases like SQL Server, SQL Server CE, MySQL, XML file, VistaDB and may be few more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASYNC Controller In MVC 4</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/async-controller-in-mvc-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 22:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/async-controller-in-mvc-4/</guid>
      <description>I have build many small applications so far in MVC to help myself in understanding the framework more deeply. Now I am planning to write a blog engine on MVC. It will not be an easy task but I will be going to learn a lot of things. As I was planning things ahead I came across a problem where I have to load my blog stats like FeedBurner readers, Facebook page likes, Google +1 count, twitter followers inside a div on the page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Skydrive REST API</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/using-skydrive-rest-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2013 21:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/using-skydrive-rest-api/</guid>
      <description>I have created a wrapper class to simplify my work with REST API. I assume that you will be using a web application. First step is to create an application at dev.live.com. Once the application is created you will have the ClientID, Client Secret and Redirect domain. We will be using a ClientID and Redirect domain. Remember that the Redirect domain value cannot have localhost. You must provide a correct domain name as after successful authentication you, the user will be redirected to the domain along with the access token.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Cloud Power To Manage Your Source Code</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/using-cloud-power-to-manage-your-source-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2013 20:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/using-cloud-power-to-manage-your-source-code/</guid>
      <description>Working on multiple projects but don’t have a good way of managing the projects then you are in danger. How you manage your source code? How you collaborate and work in teams? I have been working from home and have been in constant touch with my team members and therefore we need to come up with a solution where we can have our source code controlled properly. We do have many options like Git, TFS Express or VSS or may be another source control software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pretty Paste - Visual Studio Extension Which Makes Pretty Paste</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/pretty-paste-visual-studio-extension-which-makes-pretty-paste/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 16:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/pretty-paste-visual-studio-extension-which-makes-pretty-paste/</guid>
      <description>This is a much needed extension for every developer out there. How many times you have been yelling when you paste the code from a blog post or from an article which eventually turns out to be a nightmare for you to re-format it? I came across a VS extension that can actually get this done for me. The good thing about this extension is that it is open-source and you can extend and contribute to it to make it more awesome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adobe Photoshop v1.0.1 Source Code Now Available For Download</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/adobe-photoshop-v101-source-code-now-available-for-download/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 14:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/adobe-photoshop-v101-source-code-now-available-for-download/</guid>
      <description>Download the source code for the very 1st version and one of its kind, the legendary photo editing software Adobe Photoshop. I remember, I read somewhere that they distributed the code on floppy disks. But here it is, after more than a decade the source code is now available to public.
The source code is just 588KB!! and is hosted at computerhistory.org. You can download the complete source code here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s Inside DZONE Goodie Box</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/whats-inside-dzone-goodie-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 17:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/whats-inside-dzone-goodie-box/</guid>
      <description>I have been blogging for more than 4 years now and my articles also got published in many online tech journals, blogs and may be re-written without even my consent. I got lots of email
I have been awarded DZone MVB few years back. The DZone MVB (Most Valuable Blogger) award is a big motivation for bloggers like me. Few weeks back I received an email from DZone after they have shipped a goodie box to my address.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating A Live Tile Application In Windows 8</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/creating-a-live-tile-application-in-windows-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 11:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/creating-a-live-tile-application-in-windows-8/</guid>
      <description>Developing application for Windows 8 is fun. I love the UI and the idea of having a live tile for my application. So I try building a live tile application, but unfortunately I can’t find a simple written article or a blog post. I even found MSDN to be a bit difficult for the newbies to get the grasp in first go. There are lot of things to understand and to worked on for creating a live tile in Windows 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy New Year To All</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/happy-new-year-to-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 23:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/happy-new-year-to-all/</guid>
      <description>A blog post to wish all the readers of my blog a very happy new year!? Not my style but still….
Wish you and your family a very happy and prosperous new year!! I hope this new year bring lot of happiness to you, family and friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio 2012 Features Comparison Chart</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/visual-studio-2012-features-comparison-chart/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 02:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/visual-studio-2012-features-comparison-chart/</guid>
      <description>Visual Studio 2012 is now available and here is a chart that compares the features of different versions of Visual Studio 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attribute Routing In MVC</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/attribute-routing-in-mvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2012 14:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/attribute-routing-in-mvc/</guid>
      <description>I took a look at Stack Overflow Stack-Exchange Data Explorer that is built in MVC and is open-source application to query the Stack Exchange data dump that is being provided by Stack Exchange team in every month or few. I do have a dump, but I was more curious to know about the application that they built to query the database. And I must admit that I learned tons of things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Tools Every Freelance Developer Should Have</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/free-tools-every-freelance-developer-should-have/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2012 11:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/free-tools-every-freelance-developer-should-have/</guid>
      <description>If you are freelancing or working from home, then you must have some productivity tools which can really make your work from home a lot better. Why one has to invest in a service that can be available with no cost at all? Though some services are good enough to pay for, but I suggest one should not get them unless you really need one.
I have been blogging and in a job for now almost 4 years and as a programmer I am a really big fan of open-source projects which have made my/our life easy without spending a single dime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free e-Book: UX Guidelines For Metro Style Apps For Windows 8</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/free-e-book-ux-guidelines-for-metro-style-apps-for-windows-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 15:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/free-e-book-ux-guidelines-for-metro-style-apps-for-windows-8/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft made it available a free e-book for developers to understand UX Guidelines for Metro styled apps for Windows 8 and that too for both PC and tablets. This is an awesome resource which will let you know the basics and fundamentals while designing applications for PC annd tablets. As we all know that Windows 8 is the new OS with new UI design (metro) and it is necessary for every developer to know the basics before he starts developing the application for PC or for tablets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Postback Issue with Colorbox jQuery Plugin</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/aspnet-postback-issue-with-colorbox-jquery-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2012 15:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/aspnet-postback-issue-with-colorbox-jquery-plugin/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, while working on a project I came across a weird problem while working with Colorbox jquery plugin and ASP.NET. The problem is not only with Colorbox but also with another famous plugin called Fancybox. If you plan to use the plugine just to show dialog boxes, then this plugin works perfectly fine. Integrating the plugin with ASP.NET works fine but prevents post back if you have server controls on the colorbox dialog box (which is actually an invisible div on the page).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying .NET Application To Appharbor Using Git</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/deploying-net-application-to-appharbor-using-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 13:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/deploying-net-application-to-appharbor-using-git/</guid>
      <description>I have an account with Appharbor but never tried to deploy an application. Appharbor has an excellent integration with Github and Codeplex and if you are planning to showcase you application latest build then Appharbor is the best thing to do that. The Appharbor site has a detailed tutorial on how you can deploy your application from Github and Codeplex. But the question here is what will a programmer do if he just wants to deploy the application from his dektop or in other words if he wants to test his application which is not an open source application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrate Windows Live SignIn Support In ASP.NET</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/integrate-windows-live-signin-support-in-aspnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2012 12:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/integrate-windows-live-signin-support-in-aspnet/</guid>
      <description>Last year I wrote a post on how you can integrate OpenID support in your ASP.NET application. Few days back as usual I was chasing Windows Live SDK updates on Twitter and yes the most awaited SkyDrive API was made available to all the developers. I will be writing a post later on how to upload files using SkyDrive API.
Setting up the application To integrate Windows Live Sign-In support I have downloaded the LiveService samples from Github and take a look at ASP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MP3APP - A Web Application To Get Lyrics, Album Name, Album Art and More</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/mp3app-a-web-application-to-get-lyrics-album-name-album-art-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2012 20:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/mp3app-a-web-application-to-get-lyrics-album-name-album-art-and-more/</guid>
      <description>I was busy in few of my freelance projects and got a very rough weekends this whole month. But still I get a bit of time to work on my so called in-house project and somehow I was able to get it completed after a bit of testing. The application I built is a simple web application which will allow you to enter artist name and the song name and let you search the lyrics, album art, artist image, album name and album release date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working With Micro-ORM Dapper In MVC</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/working-with-micro-orm-dapper-in-mvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2012 12:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/working-with-micro-orm-dapper-in-mvc/</guid>
      <description>I love working with MVC but I do have a hard time working with complex data with EntityFramework (EF). I heard of using inline SQL queries in MVC but don&amp;rsquo;t know how to use it and will it have any performance issues? Few month&amp;rsquo;s back I downloaded the StackOverflow (SO) Data Explorer which is an open-source project built on MVC to explore data dump provided by SO. The thing that took my attention in that code was that they have been SQL queries to get the data from the database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infinite Scrolling In ASP.NET With jQuery</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/infinite-scrolling-in-aspnet-with-jquery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2012 12:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/infinite-scrolling-in-aspnet-with-jquery/</guid>
      <description>I didn&amp;rsquo;t create the whole solution by myself. The initial idea is from the All-In-One Code Framework sample. I was just customizing my BlogEngine and for one of the module I thought it would be nice not to use paging and I should go for infinite scrolling stuff. This idea seems cool to me and without wasting any time I just do a quick web search and I came across a solution which is a part of a All-In-One Code Framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Launches SkyDrive Application For Windows</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/microsoft-launches-skydrive-application-for-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 13:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/microsoft-launches-skydrive-application-for-windows/</guid>
      <description>On 23rd April Microsoft announces the launch of official SkyDrive application for Windows on Windows 8 blog. This is one of the most awaited applications among the developers and users. All we wanted is a simple app through which we can manage our cloud storage with ease. Download the SkyDrive app here.
Here is what available now according to this blog post:
  SkyDrive for the Windows desktop (preview available now).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 3 Ultimate Timepass For Developers</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/top-3-ultimate-timepass-for-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2012 13:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/top-3-ultimate-timepass-for-developers/</guid>
      <description>We have been programming a lot so we need some time to refresh our minds and get ourselves in a state where our mind processors can start working again more beautifully. When I am pushing myself hard I play 3 games that is on my favorite list. Though I do have many games but these are the 3 games that I play.
The World&amp;rsquo;s Largest Pac-Mac
The legendry dot-eating games Pac-Man.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome jQuery Image Plugins For Web Developers</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/awesome-jquery-image-plugins-for-web-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2012 03:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/awesome-jquery-image-plugins-for-web-developers/</guid>
      <description>I am not a web developer but still I love working with jQuery, CSS3, HTML5 and other web development frameworks. But as a programmer I love collect code snippets for my ease and store them on the cloud so I can get the access when I am in need and want to save my time while I am writing code. Out of the box I have a list of few image manipulation plugins which seems pretty impressive to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minify Your CSS &amp; Javascript With SquishIt</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/minify-your-css-javascript-with-squishit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2012 03:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/minify-your-css-javascript-with-squishit/</guid>
      <description>No one likes if their favourite site is loading up slow. Using CSS sprites instead of using individual images and minify javascript and css files is a way to minimize the request send to the server and also saves you few KBs or may be even MBs. If your site is high on using javacript and CSS then you should minimize them.
I recently used SquishIt to combine/minimize my CSS and javascript files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BingMap.JS - Jquery Plugin For Bing Maps</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/bingmapjs-jquery-plugin-for-bing-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2012 16:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/bingmapjs-jquery-plugin-for-bing-maps/</guid>
      <description>Bing maps are out there for a long time now and is getting mature pretty fast. I have used Bing maps myself in few of my projects and I remember as a first time user I have a hard time configuring it according to my project requirement. To get myself out of the overhead I searched the web for a jquery plugin, but I can&amp;rsquo;t find a single jquery plugin for Bing Maps instead I found few for Google Maps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death Of Visual Studio Installer Projects After Visual Studio 2010 And NSIS &amp; Inno Setup Installers</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/death-of-visual-studio-installer-projects-after-visual-studio-2010-and-nsis-inno-setup-installers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2012 03:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/death-of-visual-studio-installer-projects-after-visual-studio-2010-and-nsis-inno-setup-installers/</guid>
      <description>I came across an announcement made by Candy Chiang at MSDN Forums at ClickOnce and Setup &amp;amp; Deployment Projects forums.
 In Visual Studio 2010, we have partnered with Flexera, makers of InstallShield, to create InstallShield Limited Edition 2010 just for Visual Studio 2010 customers. The InstallShield Limited Edition 2010 offers comparable functionality to the Visual Studio Installer projects. In addition, you can build your deployment projects using Team Foundation Server and MSBuild.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add Google Login Support In ASP.NET With OpenID</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/add-google-login-support-in-aspnet-with-oauth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2012 17:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/add-google-login-support-in-aspnet-with-oauth/</guid>
      <description>Few years back I blogged about adding OpenID login support in ASP.NET application. This time I am blogging about adding Google login support in ASP.NET application. A friend of mine is trying to integrate multiple third party authentication support for one of the application he is developing for his client. He is using DotNetOpenAuth for Google authentication. the code I am using here is from my friend and I am sharing it with his explicit permission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML5 File Drag and Drop Upload With jQuery and ASP.NET</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/html5-file-drag-and-drop-upload-with-jquery-and-aspnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2012 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/html5-file-drag-and-drop-upload-with-jquery-and-aspnet/</guid>
      <description>I came across an article on Tutorialzine which demonstrate file drag and drop upload with jQuery and PHP. As a curious reader, I downloaded the sample files and took a look and also get it running on my LINUX VM. It worked like a charm. But I am a Windows user and .NET programmer, the question is how can I do the same in ASP.NET?
So, to get myself started I used the same downloaded files that I used to check the PHP version of the file drag and drop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Visual Studio Achievements - Bringing Some Game To The Code</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/introducing-visual-studio-achievements-bringing-some-game-to-the-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2012 13:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/introducing-visual-studio-achievements-bringing-some-game-to-the-code/</guid>
      <description>Another awesome stuff for developers from Microsoft! This past Wednesday Microsoftie Karsten Januszewski announced the Visual Studio Achievement Beta at Channel9. Guess what? as a developer, you are writing hundred lines of code every day without even getting noticed by the community!!? Well, you will get noticed now. Here is an extract from the official post from Channel9:
 Bring Some Game To Your Code!
A software engineer&amp;rsquo;s glory so often goes unnoticed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top Visual Studio Extensions</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/top-visual-studio-extensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/top-visual-studio-extensions/</guid>
      <description>Visual Studio comes up with loads of stuff making everyday life of a developer easy. But there are few extensions which Microsoft and other developers have created and are available for free to the community members. I have compiled a list of free and powerful extensions which will take your programming experience few more steps ahead with Visual Studio.
NuGet Package Manager
You should have a very good reason if you are not using this or if you are not aware what NuGet is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML 5: Show Your Support / Tell The World</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/html-5-show-your-support-tell-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2011 12:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/html-5-show-your-support-tell-the-world/</guid>
      <description>If you really love working with HTML5 the this is then time to show some support for HTML5. Use the HTML5 badge builder to create a badge and use it on your blog/website to show your support. The badge builder allows you to customize the badge with tech you use with HTML5. You can see the badge I customized with the tech under badge section on the right.
The w3.org site for HTML5 has to offer more than just a badge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Song Lyrics From LYRDB With ASP.NET MVC And JQuery</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/get-song-lyrics-from-lyrdb-with-aspnet-mvc-and-jquery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2011 14:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/get-song-lyrics-from-lyrdb-with-aspnet-mvc-and-jquery/</guid>
      <description>Most of the times I have seen people looking for song lyrics on online MP3 or lyrics database sites. Few of them provide API to fetch lyrics which is good for developers. Last.fm has a powerful API but they don&amp;rsquo;t provide any API call to fetch lyrics. The two most popular APIs on the web that I am aware of is WikiLyrics, LyricsDB (popularly known as LyrDB), there is another API from ChartLyrics but I don&amp;rsquo;t find it as useful as the other two APIs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upload and Show Image Without Post Back With Jquery</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/upload-and-show-image-without-post-back-with-jquery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2011 14:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/upload-and-show-image-without-post-back-with-jquery/</guid>
      <description>Previously in a lot of hurry I wrote a post on how to upload files in MVC3 with the help of Uploadify, a famous jQuery plugin to upload files. If you have not heard about it yet, then it is time for you to check and find out what this plugin can do for you. Appending my last post about this plugin (which was not very well written) I tried one more thing with it today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrate DISQUS For Comment Management In MVC</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/integrate-disqus-for-comment-management-in-mvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2011 18:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/integrate-disqus-for-comment-management-in-mvc/</guid>
      <description>I have been working on a MVC project which I will be using to save and manage all my code snippets. I get this plan in my head when my 160GB of HDD got crashed which holds most of my work and code. I started writing the web application in web forms and almost got it completed, but eventually changed my mind and started writing the application from scratch in MVC 3 with Razor view engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Counter: JQuery Plugin To Get Twitter, Facebook And Feed Readers Count</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/social-counter-jquery-plugin-to-get-twitter-facebook-and-feed-readers-count/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2011 16:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/social-counter-jquery-plugin-to-get-twitter-facebook-and-feed-readers-count/</guid>
      <description>Appending my previous post, I have created a plugin in JQuery to get twitter followers count, facebook likes and feed readers count. In my previous post, I have shown a way to get the counts in ASP.NET and I have created this plugin so that everyone can use and show counts on their blogs or site.
To get started add the two javascript files, one is the jquery file and the other one is the plugin file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Twitter, Facebook And Feed Readers Count In ASP.NET</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/get-twitter-facebook-and-feed-readers-count-in-aspnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2011 03:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/get-twitter-facebook-and-feed-readers-count-in-aspnet/</guid>
      <description>I am working on some web stuff these days and surfing around to look at some of the best web developer&amp;rsquo;s work around the web. As I was surfing I came across one of the most popular and reputed web tutorials site Nettus+. I am not going talking about any tutorial or article published on this site, but one thing that attracts my attention was the way they are displaying their followers count on twitter, facebook likes and RSS readers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML 5 Cheat Sheets</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/html-5-cheat-sheets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2011 03:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/html-5-cheat-sheets/</guid>
      <description>If you are working with HTML5, then there are some cheat sheets which you should refer for HTML5 syntax. Here are three different cheat sheets for HTML5.
HTML 5 Visual Cheat Sheet
HTML 5 Quick reference Cheat Sheet
HTML 5 Canvas Cheat Sheet
Download: HTML 5 - Cheat Sheets.zip (380.58 kb)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using ReCaptcha In ASP.NET WebForms And MVC</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/using-recaptcha-in-aspnet-webforms-and-mvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2011 14:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/using-recaptcha-in-aspnet-webforms-and-mvc/</guid>
      <description>ReCaptcha is now being used widely by many websites especially where there is a possibility of spamming the website, blog or a forum. Here I will show you on how you can use ReCaptcha in ASP.NET and MVC. Get a ReCaptcha Gobal Key and ASP.NET ReCaptcha DLL. Once you get the global key we are ready to go.
ReCaptcha in WebForms
Fire Visual Studio and create a new ASP.NET web forms project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling Text Changed Event In ASP.NET MVC 3 With JQuery</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/handling-text-changed-event-in-aspmvc-3-with-jquery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2011 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/handling-text-changed-event-in-aspmvc-3-with-jquery/</guid>
      <description>In my quest of learning MVC I came across many problems and here is one of them. I was trying to fire an event whenever a text changed event occurred. I am using JQuery to handle the text changed event but eventually the text changed event doesn&amp;rsquo;t seems to be working in MVC as it is working for a text box changed event in web forms. The solution I found seems to be working fine for me as I don&amp;rsquo;t want to fire an event on every key press.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angry Birds Theme For Windows 7</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/angry-birds-theme-for-windows-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2011 09:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/angry-birds-theme-for-windows-7/</guid>
      <description>If you love playing Angry Birds on your PC or on your phone, then you will also love Angry Birds theme for Windows 7. The sound effects are cool, just like the one you hear while you play the game and the wallpapers are cool too. I like the red angry bird to sit on my desktop as it is the best wallpaper I can choose among the 6 wallpapers that comes with the theme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bin Deploy ASP.NET MVC 3 Application With SQL CE 4.0 &amp; Entity Framework</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/bin-deploy-aspnet-mvc-3-application-with-sql-ce-40-entity-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2011 14:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/bin-deploy-aspnet-mvc-3-application-with-sql-ce-40-entity-framework/</guid>
      <description>A few days back Phil Haack wrote a blog post on how to bin deploy ASP.NET MVC 3 application on the web server where ASP.NET MVC 3 is not installed. Like many users I am also on shared hosting and therefore I do not have full control over IIS or the remote machine so I can install or update ASP.NET MVC 3, SQL Server CE 4.0 and other development related stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With NETMF And Netduino</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/getting-started-with-netmf-and-netduino/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2011 08:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/getting-started-with-netmf-and-netduino/</guid>
      <description>My Netduino card arrived this Sunday but I was not able to play with my new development board due to some serious &amp;ldquo;crap work&amp;rdquo; I was doing. Today I was able to run a small piece of code which blinks the user LED on the Netduino board. The code is simple enough and just like &amp;ldquo;hello world&amp;rdquo; example like we have for all other programming languages.
Here is my Netduino kit:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Be A Rockstar Freelancer</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/how-to-be-a-rockstar-freelancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 02:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/how-to-be-a-rockstar-freelancer/</guid>
      <description>A friend of mine who is a freelancer purchased the PDF version of this book and sends over me a copy to read today. If you are a freelancer or working from home then this is the book you should read and follow. I am bit lazy in reading non-tech related books or articles but this book is worth reading as compared to some other tech books. I am reading this book at the moment and I must said that this is the best book available for freelancers and for the people who are working from home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prepare Your Site For IE9 With Pinify</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/prepare-your-site-for-ie9-with-pinify/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2011 23:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/prepare-your-site-for-ie9-with-pinify/</guid>
      <description>This is great stuff. If you own a website or a blog you should use this excellent feature of pinning fav links of your site on user&amp;rsquo;s Windows 7 taskbar. Though this feature of IE9 was on hype since it&amp;rsquo;s beta realease. Now it&amp;rsquo;s time to use this feature for my blog. But before you start grab the latest stable version of the Pinify (formerly know as IE9ify) from Codeplex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syntax Highlighter In WPF</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/syntax-highlighter-in-wpf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 16:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/syntax-highlighter-in-wpf/</guid>
      <description>If you are writing code for a while now then by now you must have a lot of code snippets which you will be using in your application development, and you use them because they save a lot of development time. At this moment I have now a huge collection of code snippets which includes functions, classes, extension methods and functions that I have extracted from different open source applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Snippet: Remove Duplicates From ArrayList</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/code-snippet-remove-duplicates-from-arraylist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 02:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/code-snippet-remove-duplicates-from-arraylist/</guid>
      <description>Two methods to remove Duplicates from ArrayList.
Method 1:
private static ArrayList RemoveDuplicates(ArrayList arrList) { ArrayList list = new ArrayList(); foreach (string item in arrList) { if (!list.Contains(item)) { list.Add(item); } } return list; }  Method 2:
private static string[] RemoveDuplicates(ArrayList arrList) { HashSet&amp;lt;string Hset = new HashSet&amp;lt;string((string[])arrList.ToArray(typeof(string))); string[] Result = new string[Hset.Count]; Hset.CopyTo(Result); return Result; }   Note: I found this method on the net and therefore I am sharing it as it is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Analytics: Widget For BlogEngine.NET Powered By Google Analytics</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/blog-analytics-widget-for-blogenginenet-powered-by-google-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2011 17:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/blog-analytics-widget-for-blogenginenet-powered-by-google-analytics/</guid>
      <description>Finally, I got to know the way to show Google Analytics stats on my blog space. To know more about using Google Analytics API read their official article on using the API.
I have built a widget with the help of Analytics API to show the Google Analytics stats on my blog. The widget shows three stats at the moment (I don&amp;rsquo;t want to make the widget look complex). Below is a screenshot for the widget in action on my blog:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Live Theme For BlogEngine.NET</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/windows-live-theme-for-blogenginenet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2011 17:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/windows-live-theme-for-blogenginenet/</guid>
      <description>I have now been using BlogEngine for 2 years now and I was kinda fed up with the standard theme I have been since starting which I have modified a bit to look more prettier. I am not saying it&amp;rsquo;s bad but it&amp;rsquo;s too much now, I should do a makeover of my blog. Now the BlogEngine community is not as big and vast as that of the most popular blogging engine Wordpress and therefore it is hard to get beautiful themes for BlogEngine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Live Theme For BlogEngine.NET</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/bitly-api-shorten-urls-reverse-long-urls-get-qr-code-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2011 16:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/bitly-api-shorten-urls-reverse-long-urls-get-qr-code-image/</guid>
      <description>If you have long URLs and other and want to create short URLs then Bit.ly API can help. I wrote a wrapper class which can let me create short URLs in jiffy. I was working on Bit.ly API to create my short URLs with a click of a button (that&amp;rsquo;s for my personal use). Therefore, I ended up with a &amp;lsquo;short&amp;rsquo; class to create short URLs using Bit.ly API. What you need is a login and an apikey, which you can have one for yourself by signing up for a free account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upload Files In RAZOR With jQuery Uploadify Plugin</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/upload-files-in-razor-with-jquery-uploadify-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2011 16:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/upload-files-in-razor-with-jquery-uploadify-plugin/</guid>
      <description>A Few months back I wrote a post on how to use jQuery plugin Uploadify to upload single/multiple files without postback in ASP.NET. The program works similarly to simple file upload sites in its ease of use. Now a few days back I was working on a demo project which is on MVC 3 Razor and I use the same plugin without any problems. But the files that are being uploaded are uploaded to the root folder instead of the folder I specified to upload the files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working With Microsoft Web Helpers In MVC 3 Razor View</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/working-with-microsoft-web-helpers-in-mvc-3-razor-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2011 10:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/working-with-microsoft-web-helpers-in-mvc-3-razor-view/</guid>
      <description>Building applications with ASP.NET MVC 3 and that too with RAZOR is easy. I believe most of the programmers out there found MVC 3 with RAZOR view engine found it easy. The best things I found in the new RAZOR view engine is the code is pretty much tidy no traditional code behinds and moreover you can work with the server-side code with the start of the @ symbol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows 7: Create Jumplists In WPF Application Without Using Windows 7 API Code Pack</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/windows-7-create-jumplists-in-wpf-application-without-using-windows-7-api-code-pack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2011 14:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/windows-7-create-jumplists-in-wpf-application-without-using-windows-7-api-code-pack/</guid>
      <description>I wrote a blog post on how you can add a custom Jumplist on your Windows form application for Windows 7 platform using the Windows 7 API Code Pack, but that is for Windows Form applications running on Windows 7.
WPF makes Jumplists more simpler. You need not to add any API reference or any other reference in your project. You can just make the use of Jumplists for better navigation for your users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Free Up Gigs of Space On Your Window 7 Machine</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/how-to-free-up-gigs-of-space-on-your-window-7-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2011 03:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/how-to-free-up-gigs-of-space-on-your-window-7-machine/</guid>
      <description>I am now using Windows 7 since its beta release and so far my experience is awesome. But as a developer the hard drive space is always been a problem for me, no matter how many external drives or other stoarge devices you have connected to your machine but the disk space on the host machine is always a primary problem. Windows 7 is more stable OS in Windows family so far (I found it more stable than Win XP) and the reason it is being more stable because everytime you install a program on your Win 7 machine, it automatically creates a snapshot of the host drive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrate Bing Maps With Geonames Database And ASP.NET</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/integrate-bing-maps-with-geonames-database-and-aspnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2011 03:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/integrate-bing-maps-with-geonames-database-and-aspnet/</guid>
      <description>To locate a place on maps (Bing or Google), the best thing is to get the latitude and longitude of the location, this ensures that the place we are pinning on the map is accurate. But the big question is to where to get the latitude and longitude of the location. There might be a web service for getting the latitude and longitude of a location, but wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be nice if you just have to query a local database?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reverse Those Short URLs</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/reverse-those-short-urls/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2011 02:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/reverse-those-short-urls/</guid>
      <description>Bit.ly is one of the major short URL service provider. There are other also but Bit.ly is used by most of the users because of it&amp;rsquo;s simplicity, API and statistics. But some notorious users create short URLs for the spam sites which doesn&amp;rsquo;t make any sense to us. As you know by looking at the short URLs, they won&amp;rsquo;t reveal anything. But there is a way to get the original/long URL through ASP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9 Promises Should Be Taken Before Choosing IT Profession</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/9-promises-should-be-taken-before-choosing-it-profession/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2011 05:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/9-promises-should-be-taken-before-choosing-it-profession/</guid>
      <description>I received an e-mail from a friend of mine who is quite upset after choosing IT as his profession becasue of the list of promises in the e-mail (listed below). Well this is because he didn&amp;rsquo;t made any of the below listed promises to himself and after reading this e-mail he was more upset. Therefore, if you are willing to be an IT guy, then make sure you have made 9 promises as listed below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Snippet: Export DataGridView To Excel With Columns</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/code-snippet-export-datagridview-to-excel-with-columns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 16:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/code-snippet-export-datagridview-to-excel-with-columns/</guid>
      <description>This is among one of the best code snippet I have and using since long to export the datagridview to excel. The best part of this code snippet is that it just don&amp;rsquo;t uses the excel interop, so you need not to worry about the Office version or PIAs installed at user&amp;rsquo;s machine. What actualy is needed is just a Reflection namespace - System.Reflection and it will bind the data to the instance of the excel application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows 7 Development: Working With Task Dialog Class</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/windows-7-development-working-with-task-dialog-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2011 16:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/windows-7-development-working-with-task-dialog-class/</guid>
      <description>Last year, I blogged about few things related to Windows 7 development which includes Jump Lists and Glass Form. The Windows 7 API Code Pack comes with many other features which can be used while developing applications for Windows 7 platform. The Windows 7 API Code Pack comes with some sample applications which exposes the power of the API.
In one of my previous projects I used the Task Dialog class to use some cool looking message boxes like the one we see in Windows 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using jQuery To Get Your Tweets</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/using-jquery-to-get-your-tweets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2010 16:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/using-jquery-to-get-your-tweets/</guid>
      <description>If you are a blogger and using Twitter, then you must want to show some of your latest tweets on your blog space. I do have a custom widget for my blog which can display 3 of my latest tweets and I can customize it show more of my tweets. But the widgets cannot be used in every scenario and this is why some people find it difficult to use the widget provided by Twitter to display their tweets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding CAPTCHA In ASP.NET Application</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/adding-captcha-in-aspnet-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2010 01:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/adding-captcha-in-aspnet-application/</guid>
      <description>Using CAPTCHA was never easy for me before I got a class from an unknown user on a community forum post. I have just re-used the class to get my work done. The class is extremely easy to use and let you incorporate the CAPTCHA into your application in just few lines of code.
You can set the height and width of the CAPTCHA image while initializing the CAPTCHA class. The CAPTCHA image generated from the class can be set to the image control directly or it can be save to the local path and then set to the image control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autocomplete With jQuery and ASP.NET</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/autocomplete-with-jquery-and-aspnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2010 01:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/autocomplete-with-jquery-and-aspnet/</guid>
      <description>Building auto-complete feature with jQuery is easy and you can build this in no time. It&amp;rsquo;s your wish if you want to use ADO.NET or EF (LINQ) to get this done, it works great for all. The sample application I build is using both ADO.NET and EF. So let&amp;rsquo;s begin up getting files under one hood.
Use the below live links for jQuery auto-complete and CSS.
&amp;lt;link rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; href=&#34;http://dev.jquery.com/view/trunk/plugins/autocomplete/jquery.autocomplete.css&#34; type=&#34;text/css&#34; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script type=&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disable &#39;X&#39; Close Button On Your Windows Form Application</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/disable-x-close-button-on-your-windows-form-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2010 07:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/disable-x-close-button-on-your-windows-form-application/</guid>
      <description>Recently, someone on MSDN forums asked this question on how to disable the &amp;ldquo;X&amp;rdquo; a.k.a. close button in his windows form application so the user is forced to close the application from the cancel button on the form and not from the close button. He wanted this for his application which requires registration first before a user can start using his application.
I don&amp;rsquo;t know the answer so I bing arond a bit and find a solution posted by someone though I don&amp;rsquo;t have the name but it worked like a charm&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crystal Reports For Visual Studio 2010</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/crystal-reports-for-visual-studio-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2010 05:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/crystal-reports-for-visual-studio-2010/</guid>
      <description>Crystal reports is one of the most widely used reporting component in Visual Studio. But this time it goes missing from the final release of Visual Studio 2010. Crystal Reports for Visual Studio 2010 is now available for download to all the Visual Studio 2010 users and is for free of cost as always.
Download Links:
Download Crystal Reports for Visual Studio 2010
 Complete Package (EXE) Click Once Merge Modules Redist Installation (32 bit) Redist Installation (64 bit)  Getting Started with Crystal Reports for Visual Studio 2010</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Time Wrapper Class in C#</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/a-time-wrapper-class-in-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2010 13:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/a-time-wrapper-class-in-c/</guid>
      <description>I was just surfing the net in search for some fundoo tutorial on WPF and by chance (I don&amp;rsquo;t meant to visit that site), I get this class which I feel is pretty helpful. A simple wrapper class to conver time. the class allows you to convert:
 To Days To Hours To Minutes To Seconds To MilliSeconds  This can be pretty usefull. The class is as follows:
using System; public static class TimeSpanUtil { #region To days public static double ConvertMillisecondsToDays(double milliseconds) { return TimeSpan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extending OpenID Implementation With ASP.NET: User Information/Roles and Membership</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/extending-openid-implementation-with-aspnet-user-information-roles-and-membership/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2010 22:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/extending-openid-implementation-with-aspnet-user-information-roles-and-membership/</guid>
      <description>Last month I have blogged on how you can integrate OpenID login support in your ASP.NET aplication. Some of the reader requested me that it would be better if I could show how you can implement membership and roles with OpenID authentication. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t seems easy in the first place, because you will require a bit more informaton from the user like his name and e-mail address. So, what I am trying to show you here is how you can gather information of the user who has logged in with OpenID and then you can use that information to set roles and membership for your website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upload Multiple Files With jQuery &#39;Uploadify&#39;</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/upload-multiple-files-with-jquery-uploadify/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2010 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/upload-multiple-files-with-jquery-uploadify/</guid>
      <description>I have found many web developers seeking for help to upload a file in AJAX style, I am not a web developer but among the list of people who used to search the web for some control, way or a workaround to do this. I found a .NET control to do this, but like all good controls&amp;hellip;.it wasn&amp;rsquo;t free. But the control worth it.
But now we have an excellent open source plugin called Uploadify.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RAZOR: View Engine In ASP.NET MVC 3</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/razor-view-engine-in-aspnet-mvc-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2010 16:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/razor-view-engine-in-aspnet-mvc-3/</guid>
      <description>A new view engine is introduced in ASP.NET MVC 3 called RAZOR. You can download Preview 1 from Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s download center and get it running on your machine to check the new features in MVC 3. Just in case if you are thinking that installing MVC 3 will mess your current MVC 2 installation&amp;hellip;.No, it won&amp;rsquo;t. I came across a Webcamp video where Phil Haack with James Senior demonstrate this view engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Use Of Windows SkyDrive</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/efficient-use-of-windows-skydrive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2010 16:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/efficient-use-of-windows-skydrive/</guid>
      <description>If you are not using this free service offered by Microsoft, then stop reading and go to SkyDrive and sign in with your Live ID and get started. A whooping 25 GB of free space to put all your stuff at one place, access anytime, and anywhere you want and just in case if you are aware, which I hope you already are, why I am mentioning about skydrive here? So, here is the case&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add OpenID Login Support In Your ASP.NET Application</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/add-openid-login-support-in-your-aspnet-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2010 14:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/add-openid-login-support-in-your-aspnet-application/</guid>
      <description>Few days back I was looking at Scott Hanselman and friend&amp;rsquo;s Open Source Nerddinner project, learning and grabbing some new things from there. Apart from looking some internals I looked at the OpenID implementation. This was all a week ago and now it&amp;rsquo;s time for me to write and give some thoughts on DotNetOpenAuth. For folks who are new to OpenID I am going to demonstrate how you can implement one in your project with ease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Your e-mail Address Says About Your Computer Skills</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/what-your-e-mail-address-says-about-your-computer-skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2010 04:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/what-your-e-mail-address-says-about-your-computer-skills/</guid>
      <description>Just stumble upon this pic. Check, what it has to say about your computer skills!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diagnostic Check For ASP.NET MVC Application&#39;s Problems</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/diagnostic-check-for-aspmvc-applications-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2010 17:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/diagnostic-check-for-aspmvc-applications-problems/</guid>
      <description>Diagnosing problems in your ASP.NET MVC application is now more easy by using a single file which is included in the MVCFutures package. Download this package from CodePlex and just drag and drop a file called MVCDiagnostics.aspx in the root of your MVC application and thats it.
Press F5 and set the URL pointing to the file diagnostics file and you will be able to see a detailed information about your currently running MVC application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attach Virtual Hard Disk Automatically At Windows Startup</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/attach-virtual-hard-disk-automatically-at-windows-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2010 18:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/attach-virtual-hard-disk-automatically-at-windows-startup/</guid>
      <description>Windows 7 gives you the power to create Virtual Hard Disk (VHD). If you don&amp;rsquo;t know how to create a VHD in Windows 7 then you seriously need to learn how to unleash Windows 7 power. You can see the links in the end which will let you create a new VHD on your Windows 7 machine and there are some other recommended links.
I assume that you know or you have created a new VHD and attached or mount on your Windows 7 machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deprecated APIs In .NET 4.0</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/deprecated-apis-and-net-40/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2010 11:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/deprecated-apis-and-net-40/</guid>
      <description>A number of existing APIs are deprecated in .NET Framework 4.0. A complete listing of deprecated APIs in .NET Framework 4.0 can be found here at MSDN:
 Obsolete Types in the .NET Framework 4 Obsolete Members in the .NET Framework 4  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change Page Themes Dynamically Using JQuery Theme Roller</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/change-page-themes-dynamically-using-jquery-theme-roller/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2010 12:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/change-page-themes-dynamically-using-jquery-theme-roller/</guid>
      <description>If you are using JQuery controls like date picker, accordion, progress bar, slider, tabs, dialog etc. You can set the theme of your choice or you can also allow the user to set the theme of their choice. For those folks who don’t know about the JQuery Theme Roller, then take a look at official Jquery site demonstrating the Jquery Theme Roller. The best part is when you select the theme from the theme roller control all the JQuery controls on the page will automatically inherit the color scheme of the theme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>URL Routing With ASP.NET 4 - Web Forms</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/url-routing-with-aspnet-4-web-forms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2010 18:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/url-routing-with-aspnet-4-web-forms/</guid>
      <description>URL Routing was first introduced in .NET framework 3.5 SP1 but MVC has built-in and works pretty decently to create SEO friendly URL and prevents URL hacking. ASP.NET 4.0 is now introduced with a new feature called URL routing with web forms. URL routing help developers to create short and friendly URLs which enhance search engine page ranking. There are few other ways to create short friendly URLs like URLrewriter.net extension or if you have a physical access to IIS you can have installed URL Rewriter extension for IIS 7 to create short friendly URLs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build “Out of Browser” Applications with Silverlight</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/build-e2809cout-of-browsere2809d-applications-with-silverlight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2010 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/build-e2809cout-of-browsere2809d-applications-with-silverlight/</guid>
      <description>If you think that Silverlight applications are only intended to be run on web browsers, then you are wrong! Silverlight is now widely used to build Rich Internet Application (RIA) allowing users to work more efficiently and make a working session more interactive and attractive. As we all know a customer will always seek for a short-cut method, he will never listen to your comments or suggestions and wants everything to be done in few mouse clicks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>URL rewriting in Blog Engine.NET</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/url-rewriting-in-blog-enginenet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2010 14:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/url-rewriting-in-blog-enginenet/</guid>
      <description>was just looking for a way to get short URL’s for my blog, I used some extensions, some URLrewriter.NET but still not able to get this work. So I drop an e-mail to Scott Hanselman and was waiting for his response. If you look at Scott’s blog you will see that he has very simple URL for his blog posts which eventually get his posts higher ranks on search engine indexing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows 7 Logon Screen Changer</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/windows-7-logon-screen-changer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2010 22:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/windows-7-logon-screen-changer/</guid>
      <description>Recently I was reading an article on some Windows 7 forums on how to change Windows Logon Background. There are manual steps which helps me to change the longon background, but its tedious if I have to do it manually everytime. So I decided to make a tool which can do it for me.
I start up a new project in Visual Studio 2010 and create a new windows application. I am not writing about how I did it, I am just giving away this tool for use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Build UAC Compatible Application In .NET</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/how-to-build-uac-compatible-application-in-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2010 21:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/how-to-build-uac-compatible-application-in-net/</guid>
      <description>We all know about a feature called User Account Control (UAC) which introduced with the launch of Windows Vista. By default, UAC is enabled and provides users a better and safer computing experience, but most of the users find it irritating when the UAC prompts everytime they try to run a program. Disabling UAC is not recommended at all.
With UAC enabled programmers find it difficult to access some of the locations on the local drive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Akismet Extension For BlogEngine.NET</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/akismet-extension-for-blogenginenet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2010 20:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/akismet-extension-for-blogenginenet/</guid>
      <description>Since I have started using BlogEngine.NET I never thought of using any other open source blog engine. To me BlogEngine is the most extensible blogging platform availableat present. As a popular blogging, engine blog engine users faces a lot of spam comments. I was so totally annoyed and even after moderating comments I have to manually go and delete the comments. After some search I found an extesion from Joel Thoms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Find Whether The Machine Is of 32-Bit/64-Bit Architecture</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/how-to-find-whether-the-machine-is-32-bit-64-bit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2010 22:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/how-to-find-whether-the-machine-is-32-bit-64-bit/</guid>
      <description>The easiest way to find out the processor architecture is to use the Environment class GetEnvironmentVariable method.
Console.WriteLine(Environment.GetEnvironmentVariable(&#34;PROCESSOR_ARCHITECTURE&#34;));  This will print the processor architecture on the console window i.e. x86 and x64 for 32-bit and 64-bit respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using SQL CLR Stored Procedure To Track IP Address</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/using-sql-clr-stored-procedure-track-ip-address/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2010 00:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/using-sql-clr-stored-procedure-track-ip-address/</guid>
      <description>Recently I was asked by one of my friend how to call a web service directly from a stored procedure. He needs to track IP addresses using a stored procedures so, I suggested him two ways to call a web service using the SQL Procedure.
 Using SP_OACREATE with MSXML Create an assembly using SQL CLR using C#.  I personally tried using the first way to call a web service but was not successful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows 7 Development: Creating Jumplist In Windows 7</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/windows-7-development-creating-jumplist-in-windows-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2010 02:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/windows-7-development-creating-jumplist-in-windows-7/</guid>
      <description>I am quite fascinated with Windows 7 before even I get it started using it. Actually I have just started on a fun project for my personal use which includes jump list. Why I am doing this? To navigate and get access to the application and internet addresses I need anytime. I am tired of typing addresses and navigating to the programs I frequently use. I have just started so I thought I must blog about my jump list experience with you all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Submit Your Site To Bing Search</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/submit-your-site-blog-to-bing-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2010 03:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/submit-your-site-blog-to-bing-search/</guid>
      <description>If you want your website or blog content to be noticed or searched by Microsoft Bing search engine, then you can do this to get your work noticed. But beofre you can do this you need a Live ID a.k.a. Hotmail ID.
Go to http://www.bing.com/webmaster/WebmasterAddSitesPage.aspx
Fill up your web address and sitemap address. Though the sitemap address is optional, but I recommened to give a sitemap as it help the crawlers to crawl all the pages on your website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio Theme Generator</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/visual-studio-theme-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 01:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/visual-studio-theme-generator/</guid>
      <description>I just Got bored looking at the same code editor in Visual Studio. Same old white background and same syntax colour highlighting. So I give it a go and jump to Visual Studio options and start playing around with the option available to change the look and feel of the code editor. After trying for a while and working around with some customizations, I gave a second go and do a quick bing search in a hope that I will find some theme for my Visual Studio and Voila!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calling ASP.NET Web Service Using Jquery - Part III - Fetch Data From SQL Server</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/calling-aspnet-web-service-using-jquery-part-iii-fetch-data-from-sql-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 01:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/calling-aspnet-web-service-using-jquery-part-iii-fetch-data-from-sql-server/</guid>
      <description>My previous two posts on using Jquery for calling ASP.NET web service takes you to the basics of calling a web service using Jquery AJAX. In this last post of the series I will show hot to fetch data from the SQL Server through a web service.
In this example I am going to show on how we can fetch data from SQL Server. I am using pretty well known Adventure Works database for this example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calling ASP.NET Web Service Using Jquery - Part II - Passing Parameters</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/calling-aspnet-web-service-using-jquery-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2010 18:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/calling-aspnet-web-service-using-jquery-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post I have shown with a simple example on how you call an ASP.NET web service using JQuery. In this post I will show how you on how can you pass parameters to the web method and get the result using the web service. If you have read my previous post, you have seen that we have just called a web method which returns a simple string back to us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calling ASP.NET Web Service Using Jquery - Part I</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/calling-aspnet-web-service-using-jquery-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2010 01:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/calling-aspnet-web-service-using-jquery-part-i/</guid>
      <description>Jquery is now one of the most favorite JavaScript frameworks to play around. It offers some more advance feature to the developers and UI designers to accomplish their task easily and more conveniently. Take an example of AJAX and think where you can face the problems when you have to deal with different browsers who support XMLHTTP request and the one who don’t. I remember, I use to initialize the AJAX’s XMLHTTP object keeping in mind what will be my client’s browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passing Parameters and Loading Crystal Report Programmatically</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/passing-parameters-and-loading-crystal-report-programmatically/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 11:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/passing-parameters-and-loading-crystal-report-programmatically/</guid>
      <description>Reporting is an important part for every application. Crystal reports are widely used and also available in Visual Studio for reporting purposes. I personally never like designing application interfaces and working on web designs, it needs good designing skills which I lack and so I never put my hands on designing anything, but sometimes we have to. In crystal reports when you create a report using wizard or just adding a blank report to the project and then fetching data using code (after designing), the report works fine on the machine where you have designed and develop it and the problem occurs when you have to deploy or distribute your application with reports on multiple machines or clients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows 7 Development: Aero Effects in .NET Applications</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/windows-7-development-aero-effects-in-net-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2010 13:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/windows-7-development-aero-effects-in-net-applications/</guid>
      <description>With the launch of Windows Vista, Microsoft introduces brand new UI, eye-catching aero effects (glass effects) for their new Operating System. I have seen a lot of programmers who are much concerned about the looks of their applications. So this time with the launch of Windows 7, Microsoft provides the Windows 7 API Code Pack. The Windows 7 API Code Pack not only just allows incorporating the aero glass effect, but many other features which will let you to work more conveniently with Windows 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Server performance and NOCOUNT</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/sql-server-performance-and-nocount/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2010 20:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/sql-server-performance-and-nocount/</guid>
      <description>Performance of SQL server matters while working with large enterprise applications and where performance really bothers the business workflow. When NOCOUNT is ON, the count of rows by the execution of the query (T-SQL statements) is not returned. You must have noticed that when you perform operations by executing INSERT, UPDATE, DELETE or SELECT statements, the server returns the number of rows. The count of rows is necessary while debugging your queries, when you are done with debugging you can turn NOCOUNT ON.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single Instance of Child Forms in MDI Applications</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/single-instance-of-child-forms-in-mdi-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2010 00:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/single-instance-of-child-forms-in-mdi-applications/</guid>
      <description>In MDI application we can have multiple forms and can work with multiple forms i.e. MDI childs at a time but while developing applications we don&amp;rsquo;t pay attention to the minute details of memory management. Take this as an example, when we develop application say preferably an MDI application, we have multiple child forms inside one parent form. On MDI parent form we would like to have menu strip and tab strip which in turn calls other forms which build the other parts of the application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>using-openxml-to-insert-data-in-sql-server</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/using-openxml-to-insert-data-in-sql-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 22:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/using-openxml-to-insert-data-in-sql-server/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft SQL Server provides the mechanism to save XML data to the SQL table using OpenXML. We can use a stored procedure and pass a XML text as a string. It is useful when we have a large data in XML format and we want to save the whole data in different tables.
So first start declaring the variables. The first declare the document variable and a XML document variable as Varchar(8000) or Varchar(MAX) - It&amp;rsquo;s a same thing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enable intellisense Jquery in Visual Studio 2008</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/enable-intellisense-jquery-in-visual-studio-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2010 18:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/enable-intellisense-jquery-in-visual-studio-2008/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft with Jquery team have added the intellisense support for VS2008. I am using Jquery for the past few months, but never thought that it would be great if there would be intellisense support for Jquery. I read Scott Gu’s post of enable intellisense support for Jquery in Visual Studio. The new Visual Studio 2010 comes pre-packed with Jquery intellisense support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows 7 API Development and Training Kit</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/development-in-and-with-windows-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2010 12:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/development-in-and-with-windows-7/</guid>
      <description>I recently installed Windows 7® Ultimate on my machine and found it more soothing and reliable in terms of preformance than Windows Vista® Ultimate. As a tech enthusiast, I do some serach on the internet and found two links from Microsoft website that will allow developers to develop applications specifically for Windows 7. The Windows API code pack allows developers to develop those features which are not available with .NET Framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to plug-in a DLL into a C# project</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/how-to-plug-in-a-dll-into-a-c-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2010 16:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/how-to-plug-in-a-dll-into-a-c-project/</guid>
      <description>John Grove share a code at MSDN on how can we call DLLs methods dynamically using C# code.
The below code can further be modified and a developer can easily extend the functionality of his application to create a application which accepts DLLs as plug-ins. This concept is useful when different users have different requirements in a generalized application like in the case of famous photo editing program Photoshop from Adobe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Removing Duplicates from a List in C#</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/removing-duplicates-from-a-list-in-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2009 18:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/removing-duplicates-from-a-list-in-c/</guid>
      <description>For more details and detailed explaination of the code visit this link.
static List removeDuplicates(List inputList) { Dictionary uniqueStore = new Dictionary(); List finalList = new List(); foreach (string currValue in inputList) { if (!uniqueStore.ContainsKey(currValue)) { uniqueStore.Add(currValue, 0); finalList.Add(currValue); } } return finalList; }  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage your Azure storage with ease!</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/manage-your-azure-storage-with-ease-with-azure-storage-explorer-and-cloud-storage-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2009 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/manage-your-azure-storage-with-ease-with-azure-storage-explorer-and-cloud-storage-studio/</guid>
      <description>If your are using Windows Azure for storing files here are the tools you should love to use to manage your Azure cloud storage.
Azure Storage Explorer
And
Cloud Storage Studio
If you don&amp;rsquo;t have an Azure account, then have one HERE</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protect your .NET Applications/Libraries from &#39;Reflection&#39;</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/protect-your-net-applicationslibraries-from-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2009 00:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/protect-your-net-applicationslibraries-from-reflection/</guid>
      <description>As a programmer, you put a lot of effort to create an application and incorporate some unique features in your application, which in turn makes your application more feature rich and different from other applications. The question here is, how do you feel when you come to know that someone has played with your code and then make a same application with his name&amp;hellip;You did all the hard work and some random guy on this blue planet stole your code and takes all the credit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrieve Key from Value in Hash Table</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/retrieve-key-from-value-in-hash-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2009 02:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/retrieve-key-from-value-in-hash-table/</guid>
      <description>Working with hash tables is pretty simple but few days back I was having a problem in retrieving a key from a value in hash table. I was bit lazy to find a way myself, so I searched the net and here is what I got&amp;hellip;.a simple piece of code which lead to me to complete my task and so I thought I should share it with everyone here.
public string FindKey(string Value, Hashtable HT) { string Key = &amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo;; IDictionaryEnumerator e = HT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Sql query to write/create a file</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/use-sql-query-to-writecreate-a-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2009 14:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/use-sql-query-to-writecreate-a-file/</guid>
      <description>This SQL stored procedure will allow you to write to the file on your file system. Note the file system will be the the same on which the SQL server is running. If you are using this with your local SQL server then it will write and create files on your local file system and if you are on the remote machine, the file system will be the remote file system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T-SQL: Export Table to Excel</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/t-sql-export-table-to-excel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2009 20:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/t-sql-export-table-to-excel/</guid>
      <description>What you do to export data from SQL to excel. You use data import/export wizard or just simply execute the select query and copy the whole lot of data in an excel file with headers. Copy and paste the data in the excel sheet is the quickest possible solution I can see&amp;hellip;but what if you have to data through your code? Still there are many possible ways to accomplish this but how many lines of code you have to write to achieve this?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Background Worker in C#</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/using-background-worker-in-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2009 15:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/using-background-worker-in-c/</guid>
      <description>Performance of an application matters a lot for a developer. None of the developer wants his application freezes or crashes. But what are measures a developer should takes to keep it all good going. When I used to develop application I saw whenever I try to perform some heavy or bulky task like uploading files, copying files from place to other and other DB related but heavy task which includes CPU as well as hard drive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Word Automation in C#</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/word-automation-in-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2009 19:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/word-automation-in-c/</guid>
      <description>Here in this tutorial I have used a word document template and mail merge option of the Word to automate the word document creation.
I have use mail merge option to set the fields and make the document fill through my application. We can also set the location of the text that we want to display in the word document programmatically.
So to get started we have to first make a template which is a word document template file (.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Download albums/images from Picasa</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/download-albumsimages-from-picasa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2009 20:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/download-albumsimages-from-picasa/</guid>
      <description>Picasa is an online photo sharing portal from Google. Users from around the globe use Picasa for storing and sharing their photos online. We can view and download images from the album, but only if it is public. We cannot view private albums and also cannot download images from any of the public albums if the owner of the album has denied the access for other users to download the images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft WMI Code Creator</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/microsoft-wmi-code-creator/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2009 01:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/microsoft-wmi-code-creator/</guid>
      <description>The WMI Code Creator tool generates code that uses WMI to obtain management information or perform management tasks. You can use the tool to learn how to manage computers using WMI scripting and WMI .NET. The tool generates code that runs on the local computer, a remote computer, or a group of remote computers based on your selection from the Target Computer menu on the tool. You can also execute the generated code directly from the tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read/Write settings to INI File using C#</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/readwrite-settings-to-ini-file-using-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2009 18:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/readwrite-settings-to-ini-file-using-c/</guid>
      <description>When we design application we always face problems to save settings for the application and to achieve that we use different options available to us. A very common method to use in accordance of complexity XML files, Registry, Application.config or other/normal files. Best option is to use application configuration file but it seems that most of the people are not fully aware with the usage of the application configuration file. I will discuss late on the application configuration file a.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passing Parameters to Crystal Reports</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/passing-parameters-to-crystal-reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2009 16:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/passing-parameters-to-crystal-reports/</guid>
      <description>I found many tutorials on the internet that shows how to pass the parameters (Discreet Parameters) to crystal reports, I tried all of them, but unfortunately I didn&amp;rsquo;t get anyone of it to work. Therefore I though to give a trial on my code and eventually I got it running. I assume that you have a report ready with a parameter.
Firstly to get it running we have to use the below namespaces:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Requesting delivery/read receipt from C# using MailMessage class</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/requesting-deliveryread-receipt-from-c-using-mailmessage-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2009 15:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/requesting-deliveryread-receipt-from-c-using-mailmessage-class/</guid>
      <description>Sending e-mail through code is easy, but how do we get to know that an e-mail that we send is delivered and read by the intended recipient. When we send e-mail through code we can request a delivery notification and read receipt from the receiver, similar to the way we do in outlook. But the problem is not every mail server supports this kind of request from the code. We set a mail header while sending mail from code which is then processed by the mail server and the sender of the mail gets the intended response.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T-SQL: Recently Executed Query</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/t-sql-recently-executed-query/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 05:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/t-sql-recently-executed-query/</guid>
      <description>I am a regular reader of Pinal Dave&amp;rsquo;s blog SqlAuthority. I always found something new in his blog to work with SQL Server. Here is something I would like to share: Get the recent executed SQL Queries from SQL Server.
SELECT deqs.last_execution_time AS [Time], dest.TEXT AS [Query] FROM sys.dm_exec_query_stats AS deqs CROSS APPLY sys.dm_exec_sql_text(deqs.sql_handle) AS destORDER BY deqs.last_execution_time DESC  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Event - Windows Mobile 6.5 &amp; .NET Framework 4.0</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/microsoft-event-windows-mobile-65-net-framework-40/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2009 22:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/microsoft-event-windows-mobile-65-net-framework-40/</guid>
      <description>I attended the Microsoft developers event at NCUI auditorium in New Delhi on Windows Mobile® 6.5 and .NET Framework 4.0. Abhishek Baxi was a key speaker on Windows Mobile® 6.5. You can read his blog here. He demonstrates all the new features that Win Mob provides to the end users. How do we sync our data using cloud (Windows Live Mesh), configuring Outlook (Exchange ID) and even configure your live and other IDs, access internet using IE and develops gadgets and other application using VS2008 and 2010 on your phone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Hashtables</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/using-hashtables/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2009 21:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/using-hashtables/</guid>
      <description>Here I illustrate how to create and use hash table. Each element of hash table is a combination of Key/Value pair stored in a DictionaryEntry object. A value in a hash table can be null or contains no value but a key cannot be of null reference. Key in hash table work as an identifier for the value where you can search a hash table for a value with a specified key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laws of Computer Programming</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/laws-of-computer-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2009 02:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/laws-of-computer-programming/</guid>
      <description>Any given program, once deployed, is already obsolete.
 It is easier to change the specification to fit the program than vice versa.
 If a program is useful, it will have to be changed.
 If a program is useless, it will have to be documented.
 Only ten percent of the code in any given program will ever execute.
 Software expands to consume all available resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Import Excel to SQL Table</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/import-excel-to-sql-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2009 15:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/import-excel-to-sql-table/</guid>
      <description>Using bulk operations using code with sql can be complex, time consuming and tedious for most of the programmers. I just used a stored procedure in one of my projects instead of traversing from cell to cell and save the value in the database, so I search the net and found this SQL Stored Procedure achieve this. I have just copied and paste the code as it is.
set ANSI_NULLS ON set QUOTED_IDENTIFIER ON go --drop procedure sp_excel_Convert_Excel_To_Table --go Create procedure [dbo].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# Method: Encrypting a string using MD5 algorithm</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/c-method-encrypting-a-string-using-md5-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2009 00:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/c-method-encrypting-a-string-using-md5-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>Encrypting a string using the MD5 algorithm
This C# method will encrypt any string using MD5 algorithm. It generates the same hash as the PHP MD5() function.
using System;using System.Collections.Generic; using System.Linq;using System.Text; using System.Text.RegularExpressions; using System.Security.Cryptography; namespace EncryptString { class Program { public static string EncodePassword(string originalPassword) { Byte[] originalBytes; Byte[] encodedBytes; MD5 md5; md5 = new MD5CryptoServiceProvider(); originalBytes = ASCIIEncoding.Default.GetBytes(originalPassword); encodedBytes = md5.ComputeHash(originalBytes); return Regex.Replace(BitConverter.ToString(encodedBytes), &#34;-&#34;, &#34;&#34;).ToLower(); } static void Main(string[] args) { Console.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insert binary files to SQL server using BULK operation</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/insert-binary-files-to-sql-server-using-bulk-operation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2009 18:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/insert-binary-files-to-sql-server-using-bulk-operation/</guid>
      <description>Performing BULK operations with SQL can be useful when you are trying to insert any type of file. Don&amp;rsquo;t mess up with the complex code, just use a simple SQL query to insert any file type in SQL table.
To perform this operation first you need to have a column with datatype as varbinary(max). See below example:
Create a table with an ID and Data as columns with INT and VARBINARY(MAX) as their Datatypes respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GUIDs in C# / SQL</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/guids-in-c-sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2009 15:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/guids-in-c-sql/</guid>
      <description>GUID pronounced as goo&amp;rsquo;id - Globally unique identifier is a 128-bit integer that can be used to uniquely identify something. If you want to identify the large collection of data GUID is the best approach in my view. Also you can use the autoincremental integer to identify records, this is the basic approach programmer&amp;rsquo;s use.
GUID method can be found under the System namespace and it also provides some overloads. Here is how we can use the GUID overloads:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backup/Restore SQL database using C#</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/backuprestore-sql-database-using-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2009 15:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/backuprestore-sql-database-using-c/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft’s .NET framework provides the flexibility to Backup and Restore SQL server database. A few lines to populate the names of all the server instances, create backups and then restore the backups. The application what you see here is a part of an application, so when you create backups and restore it will use the same path hardcoded in the code itself. You can change the way you like it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set the default printer for printing programatically</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/set-the-default-printer-for-printing-programatically/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 15:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/set-the-default-printer-for-printing-programatically/</guid>
      <description>You need to print the document but you don&amp;rsquo;t want to go to control panel or printer and faxes options and just want to get it changed automatically. You can even set the shared local network printer with this code.
Just with the code you can override the system settings and change the default printer for your system.
You need to use the namespace so in order to use the DLLImport attribute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eject and Pop-in your CD / DVD with a hotkey</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/eject-and-pop-in-your-cd-dvd-with-a-hotkey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2009 16:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/eject-and-pop-in-your-cd-dvd-with-a-hotkey/</guid>
      <description>If you are annoyed with the malfunctioning of your CD/DVD ROM. This small utility will help you to eject and and again pop-in inside the ROM. Just press CTRL + Q to toggle. Place it anywhere you like on your system, I recommend to create a folder and then place a this utility inside it as it will installs on the first time you run the application and start-up with your windows the next time you boot in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shoutdown/Logoff/Hibernate/Stand By - Use CODE to do &#39;em all</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/shoutdownlogoffhibernatestand-by-use-code-to-do-em-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2009 17:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/shoutdownlogoffhibernatestand-by-use-code-to-do-em-all/</guid>
      <description>Step 1: Add the following line to use the namespace. This is necessary as we need to use the User32.dll with DLLImport attribute.
using System.Runtime.InteropServices;  Step 2: Now add the below line to your code to use the methods from the User32.dll.
[DllImport(&#34;user32.dll&#34;)] public static extern void LockWorkStation(); [DllImport(&#34;user32.dll&#34;)] public static extern int ExitWindowsEx(int uFlags, int dwReason);  Step 3: Once you complete the above two steps, you can now call the methods on button click or after some or with some particular event or the way you like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convert ASCII values from hex to characters</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/convert-ascii-values-from-hex-to-characters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2009 15:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/convert-ascii-values-from-hex-to-characters/</guid>
      <description>This C# code takes in a list of ASCII values (hexadecimal) and shows the actual characters behind, thus converting hex values to strings.
// An object storing the hex value string HexValue = &#34;4765656B7065646961&#34;; // An object storing the string value string StrValue = &#34;&#34;; // While there&#39;s still something to convert in the hex string while (HexValue.Length  0) { // Use ToChar() to convert each ASCII value (two hex digits) to the actual character StrValue += Convert.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Printing word documents without showing Print Dialog</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/printing-word-documents-without-showing-print-dialog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2009 15:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/printing-word-documents-without-showing-print-dialog/</guid>
      <description>Just one Click! and documents queued to the printer. The code will provide you the full flexiblity to set the default printer and also to set other word document settings. I used the code to convert the word document to PDF using Adobe PDF printer driver, as I was unable to get the code to convert the word files to PDF using DLLs.Cool
Download the code and don&amp;rsquo;t forget to look at the comments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Populating, Restore and Backup SQL Database using C#</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/populating-restore-and-backup-sql-database-using-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 15:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/populating-restore-and-backup-sql-database-using-c/</guid>
      <description>You want to add a functionality in your C# application to allow user to select the database to restore and taking backups of the database. C# provides the classes to allow a programmer to achieve this in the application.
Before you go and implement this feature in your application, make sure you have added the references of the following namespaces:
 Microsoft.SqlServer.Smo Microsoft.SqlServer.ConnectionInfo  Click the below link to download the full application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Import CSV File Into SQL Server Using Bulk Insert</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/import-csv-file-into-sql-server-using-bulk-insert/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2009 15:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/import-csv-file-into-sql-server-using-bulk-insert/</guid>
      <description>You have large data to import to SQL Server, and you have all the data in a CSV File (Comma Seperated Value file). Are you going to map the field one by one?
OR just use a small function od SQL to import everything in the table. But before you proceed with this you need to map each column of CSV with the one with your table column. Look at the below quick example on how to use the BULK INSERT to import CSV file data into SQL Server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convert Numbers to Words in C#</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/convert-numbers-to-words-in-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2009 13:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/convert-numbers-to-words-in-c/</guid>
      <description>Use the below code to convert numbers to words and currency to word programatically (Check the code below). Instead you can create a DLL and use it or whatever the way you like.
Usage:
Download: Num2Wrd.cs (8.30 kb)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>