<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Go on Midnight Programmer</title>
    <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/category/go/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Go on Midnight Programmer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 23:12:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/category/go/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create and Push your Docker images to Azure Container Registry</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/how-to-create-and-push-your-docker-images-to-azure-container-registry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 23:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/how-to-create-and-push-your-docker-images-to-azure-container-registry/</guid>
      <description>Docker Hub or GitHub Container Registry also known as ghcr.io is a go to platform for most of the OSS developers and teams to host their Docker images. These platforms are free for open-source software, but you might need to upgrade from the free plan to use a paid plan so that your docker image is only available for your infrastructure use and not for public use.
Azure provides Container Registry service where you can host your Docker images with ease and use the same docker pull and run command to pull and run the container on your machine, or you can also use these images to create containers when provisioning a new Web App which uses containers or with Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capture screenshot and description of a web page using Go and Chromedp</title>
      <link>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/capture-screenshot-and-description-of-a-web-page-using-go-and-chromedp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 12:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prashantkhandelwal.github.io/post/capture-screenshot-and-description-of-a-web-page-using-go-and-chromedp/</guid>
      <description>Adding or sharing a link with a snapshot of a web page is a very useful feature in Microsoft Teams or in Zoom chat. This gives a user a way to quickly look at the web page snapshot and a small description about the link.
Go has an amazing library called chromedp which allows you to perform some amazing tasks like taking screenshot, fill out a form and submit it, send key events, device emulation, script evaluation etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>